MARYAM BOZORGI

3055 Olivet St, Halifax • 902-418-9970 • mb_bozorgi@yahoo.com

LinkedIn URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryam-bozorgi-776537104/

Portfolio URL: https://w0404768.github.io/portfolio/

Professional Profile

With having 10+ years of experience working in a production IT environment as a Network Administrator in a Data center as well as being a Network Analyst with NTTData Canada Inc, highly developed skills in troubleshooting, critical thinking, multi-tasking and meeting tight deadlines to use in my journey as a Developer. Based on my past degree (Electronics) and work experience in different industries, fully aware of business needs and how to relate them to technology decisions. I have made a strong foundation of development skills by studying IT program at NSCC and doing internships at Deprolabs and The Rounds companies. I am a very motivated person to follow my strong interest and passion in Full Stack Development and getting involved in challenging projects.

Areas of Expertise and Technical Skills

Node.js • JavaScript • React • HTML5 • CSS3 • Java • PHP • Laravel • MySQL • Mongo dB • Golang Microsoft/Linux OS • ASP.NETC#• WordPress • UI/Web Design • Agile Methodologies • ITIL • Git

Highlights of Skills:

- Excellent in troubleshooting and problem solving.
- Fast learner, willing to learn new technologies.
- Excellent working in high-pressure, fast-paced and customer-centered environments.
- Highly motivated person and reputation for being innovative, creative critical thinking, decision making and multi-tasking skills.
- Demonstrated ability in achieving project success within tight deadlines.
- Highly successful team player, as well as successful working independently.
- Strong oral and written communication skills.
- Fluent English language skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Full Stack Developer – Internship (Venture for Canada) Boondoc Technologies Inc, The Rounds, Canada, Halifax

May 2019- Aug 2019

- Implemented the new designed registration process including Full Stack development in (React, GoLang, RESTFull APIs and PostgreSQL Stack)
- Used new features in React like hooks (useState, useEffect, ..).
- Implemented new RESTFull API endpoints for the new designed process.
- Researching and working on GraphQL technology to use in future.
- Used Git for source code management. (Used branch, pull request features to manage source code in the team).
- Used Node build tools like Webpack, Yarn and NPM.
- Used CSS3 and SCSS in front-end styling.

Deprolabs Technology Inc, Canada, Halifax

Jan 2019- April 2019

- Implemented new features (forgot/reset password, account confirmation, setup Email notifications) to the app including Full Stack development in (Node.js Express framework, RESTFull API endpoints, MySQL, JavaScript technologies).
- Set up the app google firebase notifications.
- Managed technical problems regarding the current functional application.

MARYAM BOZORGI P.2 **902-418-9970**

Network Consultant 2016-2017

NTT DATA Americas, Canada, Halifax

- Monitored and analyzed the worldwide network of Morgan Stanley including the North America, Europe and Asia Pacific regions containing more than 65,000 devices using monitoring tools such as Syslog Messages, CA Spectrum, SevOne and Thousand Eyes.
- Maintained, troubleshooted and administered the use of local area networks (LAN), wide area networks (WAN) and MAN networks including user related issues, device hardware and protocol issues, engage carriers for WAN circuit issues and joint troubleshooting with vendors for complex issues.
- Provided troubleshooting services to the network end users by following ITIL process and Service Now Ticketing Tool to resolve and forward tickets.

Senior Network Administrator

2006-2016

Iran Telecommunication Research center (ITRC) –Data Center, Iran, Tehran

- Implemented network setup for 6500 Cisco Series and access Switches of Data Center from level 1 to level 3 including routing protocols (BGP, OSPF, RIP), Vlan, Trunking, Etherchannel, VTP, STP, Rapid PVST, HSRP, VRRP and GLBP to apply change/new configuration.
- Setup (Cisco, Sophos, Fortigate) firewalls including Access Control List (ACL) and Network Address Translation (NAT) in large-scale based on new/change configuration.
- Monitored the network connectivity, daily performance and resource with different monitoring tools (Opmanager, Solarwinds and Nagios) and resolved the generated alerts.
- Delivered technical support (24x7) including diagnosis and resolving all network issues.

Electronics Engineer

2002-2006

Iran Telecommunication Research center (ITRC) -optical Center, Iran, Tehran

- Programmed and setup the AVR microcontrollers in STM-4 project hardware boards.
- Programmed and setup the Motorola microcontroller.

EDUCATION:

IT Web Development, Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax **Diploma**

Sept 2017 – April 2019

- Implemented and deployed full-stack (authenticated) web app (React in front-end) providing API endpoints by Node.js and MongoDB available at https://w0404768.herokuapp.com.
- Experienced server-side programming like PHP, PHP MVC, Express, Laravel Framework, Node.js, and ASP.Net (MVC).
- Implemented RESTFull API endpoints in Node.js, ASP.NET.
- Experienced working with JavaScript libraries (React framework) to implemented web page including search, listing and showing movie details by consuming tymaze API.
- Experienced object-oriented programming by Java in different projects (implementing different games).
- Skilled in HTML5 and CSS and JavaScript in implementing variety of web pages.
- Skilled in SQL databases as well as no-SQL databases such as MongoDB.
- Practiced User Interface and Web Design principles (Usability, Responsive design).
- Experienced WordPress Theme and Plugins customization.

Bachelor's degree in Electronics, RAZI University of Kermanshah, IRAN

1997-2002

CERTIFICATION:

Cisco Certified Network Associate CCNA (Routing and Switching), Halifax CCNA Security, Halifax

2017-2020 2017-2020

2017-present

ITIL, Halifax